

# RICHIE HOLSENBACK

FRONT-END DESIGN

# CONTACT

RICHIEHOLSENBACK.GITHUB.IO/
(334)707-9242
RICHIEHOLSENBACK@GMAIL.COM
GITHUB.COM/RICHIEHOLSENBACK
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RICHIE-HOLSENBACK

# SKILLS AND RELEVANT CLASSES

#### Tech Stack:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- ReactJS
- Git and GitHub
- Visual Studio Code
- NPM
- JSON Server
- Firebase
- Figma
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Semantic UI

### Experienced in:

- Prototyping
- Wire framing
- Information Architecture
- User and Usability Testing
- Journey Mapping

#### The Adobe Creative Suite, including:

- Photoshop
- Lightroom
- Illustrator
- Premiere Pro
- After Effects
- Audition
- InDesign

# ABOUT ME

I am a creative minded UI/UX designer with experience in React, Javascript, HTML, CSS and Sass. I enjoy working with teams to create attractive and functional applications that are user focused and user tested. I pride myself in being adaptable, being a team player and having strong leadership skills.

Before beginning a career in UI/UX Design, I worked in digital media and social media marketing. I love the marrying of creative and technical mindedness that those fields require. UI/UX design has offered a way to further the skills I obtained from those roles in the best way. The ever-expanding space to grow and learn as a designer and developer is the thing that makes me most excited about the future in this industry.

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

## **NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL**

FRONT-END UI/UX DEVELOPER | AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop dynamic single-page applications using React in addition to modern ES6+ JavaScript
- Learned fundamentals such as HTML, CSS, JSON, modular code, reusable components, database structure and using Entity Relationship Diagrams
- Work with team members to create sites with user experience in mind, lead user testing sessions in order to gain knowledge on how to improve user interface and enhance the site based on those results
- Exposed to an Agile environment through frequent group projects including daily stand ups, planning, ticket assignments and problem solving
- Used Githib to perform and review pull requests to ensure working code free of merge conflicts

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

## LAUGH TRACK

## GITHUB.COM/RICHIEHOLSENBACK/LAUGHTRACK

Laugh Track is a React-based web application in which comedians can create and engage with a community, workshop new material or improve older jokes and showcase events they are hosting. The project came from market research in what would help comedians improve and become as successful as possible with tools to help network, organize and showcase their talent.

#### **OURFLIX**

## RICHIEHOLSENBACK.GITHUB.IO/OURFLIX

Ourflix is another React JS based-web application designed to help users skip the hour long conversation of, "What should we watch tonight?" Users can log in through firebase, become friends, swipe through a library of movies and shows on Netflix to determine what they're interested in watching, and compare what movies they have both liked. You can get details about the movies, check out the IMDB page or head straight to Netflix to watch the movie or show.

# GROUP PROJECTS

### C43 CLASS WEBSITE

NSS-DAY-COHORT-43.GITHUB.IO/

The C43 Class site was a project for the Nashville Software School. We needed an attractive, functional site to display the many talented individuals in out cohort. We created user personas, wireframes, and mockups then user tested our design. When we had a final design, our team divided up the tasks to be completed and worked as a team to code the site into being. I worked on the technology section and organized the database of technology learned and the student information.

#### NUTTYSHELL

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/NSS-DAY-COHORT-43/HALLO-TWEEN-TOWN

This project was completed twice, the first round was a collaboration between 4 team members using traditional JavaScript, HTML and CSS. The Second round utilized React JavaScript as well as component libraries to help with styling. We created a wireframe, an ERD and group coded the welcome page and overall design of the site.

- In the first round, I was responsible for creating the events section of the app. The section hit MVP when a user could create an event with a title, location, date, time and description of that event. They must also be able to edit or delete their own events entirely.
- In the second round, I utilized React to create a dynamic messaging feature. This section hit MVP when a user could send a message that all other users could view in an updating feed. The user was also able to delete their own messages, but not those of another user.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SMILE DIRECT CLUB

SOCIAL MEDIA/ONLINE-CONTENT SPECIALIST | OCT 2019 - AUG 2020

- Collaborate with creative and development teams in an iterative process to ensure final results matched the goal of the project
- Plan overall brand strategy as well as individual pieces of content that conveyed the overall message that SmileDirectClub wanted to convey
- Monitor sentiment of customer base and made changes based on feedback as it related to content previously posted

# CUSTOMER CARE FLOOR SUPPORT/SPECIALIST | APR 2018 - OCT 2019

- Assisted team members as they interacted with customers instructing them of the company's standard operating procedures, software and specialty cases
- Created new solutions and procedures that ensured that customers were being assisted, increasing efficiency and decreasing overall time spent on cases by 22%
- Follow up with individual customers to find solutions more geared towards their individual needs and desires

## GOTTA GUY MARKETING

MARKETING ASSOCIATE | JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

- Mockup designs for external clients to present and rationalize design decisions
- Study market trends in different cities around the United States to understand which strategies would be best suited to individual areas
- Ensure that all advertising materials were ADA compliant and accessible to all who would receive the information

## RICHIE HOLSENBACK PRODUCTIONS

OWNER | MAY 2015 - PRESENT

- Storyboard a vision with clients that I would then turn into a full length film, photoshoot or design
- · Collaborate with brands to create content that suited their specific needs for a project while maintaining their corporate branding
- · Organize and maintain a large database of large files with accessibility and efficiency in mind

# EDUCATION

## UI/UX DESIGNER, FRONT END DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | AUG 2020 - PRESENT

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, MAJOR IN FINANCE

AUBURN UNIVERSITY | AUG 2011 - MAY 2016